amsa.gov.au 2017-06-08

# Condensed Privacy Policy - Australian Maritime Safety Authority (AMSA)

  * Home
  * Condensed Privacy Policy

#### How we handle your personal information

**This is a summarised version of our privacy policy which tells you how we collect and use information. You can read the** **complete policy** **here.** ****

### Scope

The condensed privacy policy applies to personal information collected by the Australian Maritime Safety Authority (AMSA).

AMSA has adopted the layered privacy policy format. This document provides you with an overview of how we handle your personal information. Our complete Privacy Policy can be accessed on our website. 

### Personal Information Handling Practices

**Collection**  
We usually collect personal information about individuals directly from those individuals or their authorised representatives.  
We sometimes collect personal information from a third party or from a publicly available source, but only if:

  * the individual has consented to such collection, 
  * we are required or authorised by law to collect information from someone other than the individual, or
  * it is unreasonable or impracticable to collect the information from the individual. 

We only collect personal information for purposes which are related to our functions or activities under legislation related to and enabling AMSA's operations, and only when it is necessary for or directly related to such purposes. We only collect information by lawful and fair means. 

### Use of personal information collected

Any personal information you choose to provide will only be used for the purpose for which it was provided and will not be disclosed to other persons or organisations without your prior consent unless required by law.  

The internet is an insecure medium and users should be aware that there are inherent risks transmitting information across the Internet.  
Information submitted unencrypted via electronic mail or web forms may be at risk of being intercepted, read or modified. If you do not wish to email or send an online form to AMSA, you can send mail by post.

### Use and disclosure

Subject to the following paragraph, we only use and disclose personal information for the purposes for which we collected it - purposes which are directly related to one of our functions or activities.  

Beyond this, we do not use personal information, or give personal information about an individual to other Government agencies, private sector organisations or anyone else, unless one of the following applies:

  * the individual has consented
  * the individual would reasonably expect AMSA to use or disclose the information for the secondary purpose and the purpose is related (or directly related in the case of sensitive information) to the purpose for which it was collected
  * we are required or authorised by law or by an order of a court/tribunal
  * we believe that the use or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary for one or more enforcement related activities conducted by, or on behalf of, an enforcement body
  * it will prevent or lessen a serious and imminent threat to somebody's life or health, or where it is necessary to assist with the location of a person who has been reported missing
  * it is necessary for the establishment, exercise, or defence of a legal or equitable claim or in relation to an alternative dispute resolution process.

### Data security

We take steps and use up-to-date techniques and processes which meet current government requirements to protect the personal information we hold against loss, unauthorised access, use, modification or disclosure, and against other misuse. These steps include maintaining up-to-date computer and network security systems with appropriate firewalls, access controls and passwords to protect electronic copies of personal information, and securing paper files and physical access restrictions.  

When the personal information that we collect is no longer required, we destroy or delete it in a secure manner, in accordance with the AMSA’s Records Disposal Authority _._

### Website Privacy Policy

#### Information collected

When you browse this website, our system may automatically make a record of your visit and log the following information for statistical purposes: 

  * your server address;
  * top level domain name (e.g.: .com, .net, .gov, .au, etc);
  * the type of browser and operating system you used;
  * date and time of your visit;
  * the previous site visited;
  * which pages are accessed;
  * the time spent on individual pages and the site overall; and
  * which files were downloaded.

This information is analysed to determine this website's usage statistics.  

However, no attempt will be made to identify individual users except where a law enforcement agency (e.g. the Australian Federal Police) exercises a warrant to inspect our service provider's log files.  

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily choose to participate in an activity through this website that involves the provision of personal information, such as:

  * sending electronic mail to this website;
  * participating in a survey on this website;
  * suggesting a link from this website to an external website.

If you choose not to participate in these activities, your choice will in no way affect your ability to use this website.  

#### Cookies  

A cookie is a small file sent by AMSA’s web server onto the user's web browser software when the user accesses this website. (An explanation of cookies generally can be found at the site of the Australian Privacy Commissioner.)  

Some parts of this website may use a cookie to maintain contact through a session. The cookie allows AMSA to recognise you as an individual as you move from one page of this website to another. This cookie will expire on the close of your browser session or on the closing down of your computer.  

Most Internet browsers are pre-set to accept cookies. If you prefer not to receive cookies, you can adjust your Internet browser to disable cookies or to warn you when cookies are being used.  

No attempt will be made to identify anonymous users unless legally compelled to do so, such as in the event of an investigation, where a law enforcement agency may exercise a warrant to inspect the Internet Service Provider's log files.   

#### Other sites  

This site contains links to external websites and this privacy statement does not extend to those external websites. AMSA is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of external websites. For more information, refer to our disclaimer statement.

#### Your choices

You can access the personal information that we hold about you, and you can ask us to correct the personal information we hold about you. For more information, see our complete Privacy Policy – ‘access and correction’.   

If you are listed on one or more of our stakeholder email lists you can opt out at any time. You can unsubscribe by using the ‘unsubscribe’ options noted in our emails.   
You may interact with us anonymously or by using a pseudonym, unless we are required or authorised by law to deal with you as an identified individual or it is impracticable for us to deal with you in an unidentified manner. 

#### Our obligations

AMSA is bound by the [Australian Privacy Principles](http://www.oaic.gov.au/privacy/privacy-resources/privacy-fact-sheets/other/privacy-fact-sheet-17-australian-privacy-principles) in the Privacy Act.   

For more information see our complete Privacy Policy.  

AMSA’s information management tool for general stakeholders is called the AMSA Community Directory. Please read the AMSA Community Directory Policy.

#### How to contact us or the Privacy Commissioner

For further information you can submit an email via the contact us page, or alternatively you can write to us at:   

Privacy Officer  
Australian Maritime Safety Authority  
GPO Box 2181  
Canberra City ACT 2601  

#### Contacting the Privacy Commissioner  

Advice about the Internet and personal information can be found on the [Privacy Commissioner's website](http://www.privacy.gov.au/).
